In this video, we will practically see inheritance.
I have to give an example of Circle and Selander, so already I have a class full circle here which
is having a property radius and three met her father ADR.
Then perimeter and circumference.
I have not read anything constructor in this class, but I mean, the property is public so that we
can directly access it.
We will be discussing about the constructor's in the next menials.
So the total goes to.
Tell me, have a class called certain knowledge does achieve inheritance.
No.
Let us see an example of inheritance.
I a like class four cylinder that extends.
Circle.
So this class will get all the features of our circle class means that the property and all these materials
are available inside the cylinder class also.
And because all of them are public, they are also accessible.
All cylinders should also have its own properties.
So I will declare properties.
So the property's height, so to make a death double.
There's only one method I will vote on that is from volume to calculate volume.
So whole volume is calculated.
It will return area multiplied by pite.
See, I'm able to call this maturity Yamit hard because this area mutatis present an inside cylinder
glass also because it is boring it from circle class.
So this idea multiplied by height does is sufficient to look at the demonstration?
No, I will create the object of cylinder glass and I will call volume method and I will show you inside
mean matured create an object of cylinder glass, see a sign new cylinder is created.
Now I should initialize the properties.
So Cylinder's Radiuses seven and Cylinder's hiatus.
Then next, I will display volume of a cylinder she got will you let us run it?
Yes, I got the volume here.
That is fifteen.
Thirty nine is the volume.
I will call Eddie, I'm a third also.
So here I will give a label that is volume.
Then after this, I will call Ethereum a Tuttle's printing C dot India.
Let us run it.
Yes, I got volume as well as area of cylinder.
I will enter and debug more and show you how this is working, because this area matters present inside
circle class legacy, what is really happening?
I'll put a break point here, then I will enter and go debug mode, press seven.
Then again at seven.
Now you can see the value of radius radiuses seven.
And the value of high distance.
If I go up into the glasses and highlight this radius, it's not showing anything because this code
is not yet active now.
And Cylinder Morwood is also not showing anything can let us enter into this Cedartown volume matter.
So if I press S7, it will enter into print and so I should press shift F seven.
So it will enter into volume Atun.
Yes, it is calling volume a total four cylinder class.
And if I put a cursor on heighted assuring 10 and garcelon radius it is showing seven, she one of the
matter of this class is being used now.
So it is showing this properties with some values.
So while you morsal in this car.
So let us move next.
I'm on this line.
That's S7.
No, you can see that area Methode of the circle is called because from this volume, Matari was calling.
Edith thought of finding the area, then multiplied by height F seven.
Now back to William.
Back to main method next, I will enter into a.D.A method.
So shift F seven, who it is calling area method of a circle.
Yes, because that is the only area method we have.
See.
I am calling it turn up on a cylinder because I have a reference of cylinder, an object of cylinder.
So when I see a seat or area than the area of a circle matre this car so that this, we can understand
that this, the cylinder class is boring the features of a circle class.
It is boring all the properties and methods.
So that's all in this video.
I have given Valon the example for a circle and Selander then.
Now rest of the examples I will give them as a student exercises.
So following me, those will be on in exercises.
So you complete ludic situs.
That's a.